Guide to the Michael Ellis Papers, 1937-1985 CTC.1977.02
ULS Archives & Special Collections
- Broadway and Off-Broadway Productions, 1948-1969; VIII.
  - The Paisley Convertible, 1967; 10.
    - Box office statements (Box 13, Folder 12)
    - Budget (Box 13, Folder 13)
    - Casting - Correspondence and agency lists (Box 13, Folder 14)
    - Casting - Interviews and schedules (Box 13, Folder 15)
    - Casting - Photographs (Box 13, Folder 16)
    - Company directory (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - Contracts and related correspondence - Alvin Colt (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - Contracts - James Hammerstein (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - Contracts - Jo Mielziner (Box 14, Folder 4)
    - Contracts - Cast (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - Contracts - Theatre (Box 14, Folder 6)
    - Contracts - Miscellaneous (Box 14, Folder 6)
    - Production schedules (Box 14, Folder 8)
    - Props, lighting, costumes, and ground plan (Box 14, Folder 9)
    - Tickets - Opening night (Box 14, Folder 10)
    - Happy Bed Company - Financial statements (Box 14, Folder 11)
    - Happy Bed Company - Insurance (Box 14, Folder 12)
    - Happy Bed Company - Prospective investors correspondence (Box 14, Folder 13)
    - Happy Bed Company - Investors correspondence (Box 14, Folder 14)
    - Happy Bed Company - Investors correspondence regarding reduction of capitalization (Box 14, Folder 15)
    - Happy Bed Company - Investors lists and Limited Partnership Agreements (Box 14, Folder 16)
    - Happy Bed Company - Taxes (Box 14, Folder 17)
  - The Girl in the Freudian Slip, 1967; 11.
    - Bucks County production as Linda Stone is Brutal reviews, May 18-31,1964 (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - Productions - Various programs, 1967 (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - Productions - Publicity and reviews (Box 15, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence - re Linda Stone is Brutal: Misc., 1963-1965 (Box 15, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence - re Linda Stone is Brutal - Paul Ford, 1965 (Box 15, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence - re Linda Stone is Brutal - David B. Silberman, 1963-1965 (Box 15, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence - re Linda Stone is Brutal - Legal, 1964 (Box 15, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence - Miscellaneous, 1964-1967 (Box 15, Folder 8)
    - Correspondence - William F. Brown (Box 15, Folder 9)
    - Correspondence - Marc Daniels, 1964-1967 (Box 15, Folder 10)
    - Correspondence - Arthur Godfrey, 1965-1967 (Box 15, Folder 11)
    - Correspondence - James B. McKenzie, 1967 (Box 15, Folder 12)
    - Correspondence - Russel Nype, 1967 (Box 15, Folder 13)
    - Correspondence - Walter Slezak, 1966 (Box 15, Folder 14)
    - Correspondence - Ethelyn R. Thrasher, 1966-1967 (Box 15, Folder 15)
    - Correspondence - Opening night in New York City (Box 15, Folder 16)
    - Correspondence - Closing in New York City (Box 15, Folder 17)
    - Advertising for New York City (Box 15, Folder 18)
    - Booking agreements and related miscellany - Coconut Grove Playhouse and Booth Theatre (Box 15, Folder 19)
    - Budget (Box 15, Folder 20)
    - Casting - Correspondence (Box 15, Folder 21)
    - Casting - Miscellaneous (Box 15, Folder 22)
    - Casting - Photographs (Box 15, Folder 23)
    - Company directory (Box 15, Folder 24)
    - Contracts and related correspondence - Linda Stone is Brutal (Box 15, Folder 25)
    - Contracts and related correspondence - William F. Brown (Box 15, Folder 26)
    - Contracts and related correspondence - Miscellaneous (Box 15, Folder 27)
    - Production schedules (Box 16, Folder 1)
    - Set designs (Box 16, Folder 2)
    - Tickets - Opening night requests and lists (Box 16, Folder 3)
    - Slip Company - Bank statements and cancelled checks (Box 16, Folder 4)
    - Slip Company - Insurance (Box 16, Folder 5)
    - Slip Company - Investors and potential investors correspondence (Box 16, Folder 6)
    - Slip Company - Investors, lists, and offering circular (Box 16, Folder 7)
    - Slip Company - Taxes (Box 16, Folder 8)
  - Sweet Eros and Witness, 1968; 12.
    - Program - Gramercy Arts Theatre in New York City, 1968-1969 (Box 16, Folder 9)
    - Reviews - Sweet Eros: Café Act IV production at International Experimental Theatre Festival at Brandeis University, August 1968 (Box 16, Folder 10)
    - Publicity and reviews - Ellis' New York production (Box 16, Folder 11)
    - Correspondence - Miscellaneous, 1968-1969 (Box 16, Folder 12)
    - Correspondence - Legal, 1968-1970 (Box 16, Folder 13)
    - Bills, 1968-1969 (Box 16, Folder 14-17)
    - Stage manager's vouchers and petty cash records (Box 17, Folder 1)
    - Box office statements (Box 17, Folder 2)
    - Budget (Box 17, Folder 3)
    - Contracts and related correspondence - Terrence McNally (author) (Box 17, Folder 4)
    - Contracts and related correspondence - Actors Equity (Box 17, Folder 5)
    - Contracts and related correspondence - Designers, staff, and theatre (Box 17, Folder 6)
    - Photographs (Box 17, Folder 7)
    - Props and lighting cue sheets (Box 17, Folder 8)
    - Salary records - Workmen's compensation forms (Box 17, Folder 9)
    - Miscellaneous - not financial (Box 17, Folder 10)
    - B.B. Company - Bank statements and cancelled checks, 1968-1969 (Box 17, Folder 11-12)
    - B.B. Company - Checkbook stubs (Box 17, Folder 13)
    - B.B. Company - Financial statements (Box 17, Folder 14)
    - B.B. Company - Insurance (Box 17, Folder 15)
    - B.B. Company - Royalties (Box 17, Folder 16)
    - B.B. Company - Taxes (Box 17, Folder 17)
  - Ceremonies in Dark Old Men, 1969; 13.
    - Productions - Negro Ensemble Company at St. Marks Playhouse in New York City: Programs, reviews, and publicity, February 1969 (Box 18, Folder 1)
    - Productions - Pocket Theatre in New York City (Ellis production), April 28, 1969 (Box 18, Folder 2)
    - Productions - Ravinia Festival, August 20-31, 1969 (Box 18, Folder 3)
    - Productions - Greater Hartford Jewish Community Center in West Hartford, Connecticut, November 3, 1969 (Box 18, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence - Miscellaneous, 1969-1971 (Box 18, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence - Lonne Elder (author), 1969 (Box 18, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence - Legal (Box 18, Folder 7)
    - Actor's Equity (Box 18, Folder 8)
    - Advertising (Box 18, Folder 9)
    - Bills - Company bills, 1969 (Box 18, Folder 10-15)
    - Bills - Company bills, 1969-1970 (Box 19, Folder 1-5)
    - Bills - Receipted bill A-K (Box 19, Folder 6-8)
    - Bills - Receipted bill L-Z (Box 20, Folder 1)
    - Box office statements (Box 20, Folder 2)
    - Budget (Box 20, Folder 3)
    - Casting (Box 20, Folder 4)
    - Contracts and terminations - Actors and staff (Box 20, Folder 5)
    - Contracts - Rentals (Box 20, Folder 6)
    - Costume List (Box 20, Folder 7)
    - Photographs (Box 20, Folder 8)
    - Prop Lists (Box 20, Folder 9)
    - Royalty waivers (Box 20, Folder 10)
    - Stage manager's daily reports (Box 20, Folder 11)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 20, Folder 12)
    - A.K. Company - Bank statements, 1969-1970 (Box 20, Folder 13-15)
    - A.K. Company - Financial statements, 1969-1970 (Box 21, Folder 1)
    - A.K. Company - Insurance (Box 21, Folder 2)
    - A.K. Company - Investors, 1969-1980 (Box 21, Folder 3)
    - A.K. Company - Taxes, 1969, 1977-1980 (Box 21, Folder 4)
  - Angela, 1969; 14.
    - Tryouts - Augusta Barn Theatre, August 1968 (Box 21, Folder 5)
    - Tryouts - Adelphi University Little Theatre (as The Toy Boy) (Box 21, Folder 6)
    - Tryouts - Shubert in New Haven, October 1969 (Box 21, Folder 7)
    - Tryouts - Wilbur in Boston, October 1969 (Box 21, Folder 8)
    - New York production - Music Box, October 29, 1969 (Box 21, Folder 9)
    - Correspondence - Miscellaneous, 1967-1969 (Box 21, Folder 10)
    - Correspondence - Sumner Long (author), 1966-1968 (Box 21, Folder 11)
    - Correspondence - Elliot Martin (co-producer), 1968-1969 (Box 21, Folder 12)
    - Correspondence - Jack Ragotsky (director), 1968-1969 (Box 21, Folder 13)
    - Correspondence - Legal, 1968-1969 (Box 21, Folder 14)
    - Opening Night Telegrams (Box 21, Folder 15)
    - Budget (Box 21, Folder 16)
    - Casting - Correspondence (Box 21, Folder 17)
    - Casting - Miscellaneous (Box 21, Folder 18)
    - Casting - Photographs (Box 21, Folder 19)
    - Contracts and related correspondence (Box 21, Folder 20)
    - Script rewrites and comments (Box 21, Folder 21)
    - Angela Company - Financial statements, 1969 (Box 21, Folder 22)
    - Angela Company - Investors and prospective investors (Box 21, Folder 23)
    - Angela Company - Miscellaneous (Box 21, Folder 24)
  - Who's Happy Now?, 1969; 15.
    - Productions - Washington DC Theatre Club, (not ME's production), March 1969 (Box 22, Folder 1)
    - Village South Theatre - Program, publicity and reviews, 1969 (Box 22, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence - Miscellaneous, 1968-1970, 1979 (Box 22, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence - Oliver Hailey (author) includes contract and partnership agreements (Box 22, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence - AAUW Juneau in Alaska, production photos and clippings, November 11, 1969 (Box 22, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence - Opening night greetings (Box 22, Folder 6)
    - Bills - Stage manager's (Box 22, Folder 7)
    - Bills - Miscellaneous (Box 22, Folder 8)
    - Box office statements (Box 22, Folder 9)
    - Casting (Box 22, Folder 10)
    - Contracts - Stanley Pager (director) and related correspondence (Box 22, Folder 11)
    - Contracts - Theatre and related correspondence (Box 22, Folder 12)
    - Contracts - Miscellaneous (Box 22, Folder 13)
    - Opening night tickets and press list (Box 22, Folder 14)
    - Miscellaneous non-financial materials (Box 22, Folder 15)
    - Precious Company - Bank statements and cancelled checks (Box 22, Folder 16)
    - Precious Company - Financial statements (Box 22, Folder 17)
    - Precious Company - Insurance (Box 22, Folder 18)
    - Precious Company - Investors correspondence and Limited Partnerhsip Agreements (Box 22, Folder 19)
    - Precious Company - Taxes (Box 22, Folder 20)
- Plays Considered for Production, 1958-1967; IX.
  In this series are nineteen plays, arranged alphabetically. Only five of the plays have files of any consequence: Beer Island - production cancelled; Daphne in Cottage D - Ellis withdrew as co-producer; Line - NY production plans dropped; The Name of the Game - NY production plans dropped twice; What Did We Do Wrong - Ellis withdrew before NY production. Among the 14 plays remaining are Mask and Gown, cross-country tour co-produced by Ellis, begun after the Bucks County production; Twelve Angry Men, world premiere at Bucks County; and Wait a Minim, in which Mary Ellis was an investor. Some plays were only considered because of a friend's involvement. In some cases, Ellis' involvement is not clear.
  - Beer Island, 1.
    - Correspondence - Miscellaneous, 1966-1967 (Box 23, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence - Shelley Berman, 1966-1967 (Box 23, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence - Kirk Douglas, 1966 (Box 23, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence - Van Heflin, 1966-1967 (Box 23, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence - Prospective directors (Box 23, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence - Legal, 1966-1968 (Box 23, Folder 6)
    - Budget (Box 23, Folder 7)
    - Casting - Agency submissions (Box 23, Folder 8)
    - Casting - Interviews (Box 23, Folder 9)
    - Casting - Miscellaneous lists (Box 23, Folder 10)
    - Casting - Photographs A-K (Box 23, Folder 11)
    - Casting - Photographs L-Z (Box 23, Folder 12)
    - Casting - Readings schedules (Box 23, Folder 13)
    - Casting - Understudies (Box 23, Folder 14)
    - Contracts - Miscellaneous correspondence and basic production contract form (Box 23, Folder 15)
    - Props (Box 23, Folder 16)
    - Script notes and comments (Box 23, Folder 17)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 23, Folder 18)
    - Beer Company - Investors' correspondence (Box 23, Folder 19)
    - Beer Company - Investors' offering circular and Partnership Agreement form (Box 23, Folder 20)
  - Daphne in Cottage D Daphne Company, 1967; 2.
    - Correspondence - Miscellaneous, 1965-1968 (Box 24, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence - Martine Bregman, 1965-1967 (Box 24, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence - Edward Chodorov, 1965-1966 (Box 24, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence - Opening night benefit at the Hopkins Center, 1966 (Box 24, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence - Postponement of production (Box 24, Folder 5)
    - Advertising and publicity (Box 24, Folder 6)
    - Bills (Box 24, Folder 7)
    - Budget (Box 24, Folder 8)
    - Casting - Correspondence (Box 24, Folder 9)
    - Casting - Submissions and readings (Box 24, Folder 10)
    - Casting - Photographs (Box 24, Folder 11)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 24, Folder 12)
    - Daphne Company - Miscellaneous bank records (Box 24, Folder 13)
    - Daphne Company - Miscellaneous financial records (Box 24, Folder 14)
    - Daphne Company - Investors correspondence (Box 24, Folder 15)
- Scripts, X.
  There are thirty-nine titles arranged alphabetically in this series. Includes scripts of Ellis productions and other plays in which he had some interest of varying degree. Various titles appear in several versions, of which the most interesting is S.J. Perelman's The Beauty Part (6 versions, final version not included). Of eight stage manager's books included, two are Ellis' - The Body Beautiful and Magnolia Alley.
  - The Advocate, 1.
    - Early version - Before I Sleep (Box 24, Folder 16)
    - Revised Final script, August 1963 (Box 24, Folder 17)
    - The American Dame: A Play/Out - Docudrama by Philip C. Lewis (Box 27, Folder 1)
    - Angela: A Comedy in Three Acts - Script precedes summer tryout, by Sumner Arthur Long, 1968 (Box 27, Folder 2)
  - The Beauty Part, 2.
    - Earliest version - Mimeo (Box 27, Folder 3)
    - Earliest version with extensive penciled revisions and substitute leaves (Box 27, Folder 4)
    - Typescript incorporating holograph revisions of folder 4 version (Box 27, Folder 5)
    - "Old Act I" - A further revision of version 3 (Folder 5). Carbon typescript (Box 27, Folder 6)
    - Revised Act I - A further revision of version 4 (Folder 6). Typescript (Box 27, Folder 7)
    - "1st revision, Act I only – Old Act II" - Carbon typescripts (Box 27, Folder 8)
    - Final complete version - Carbon typescript (Box 27, Folder 9)
    - Final complete version as above - Mimeo (Box 27, Folder 10)
    - "Pages removed from Perelman script" - written on sheet appended to 1st page. Mimeo / typescript (Box 27, Folder 11)
    - Typescript leaves with revisions or substitute leaves - Some revisions are incorporated in the 1963 Samuel French edition (Box 27, Folder 12)
  - Beer Island: A Play in Three Acts, 3.
    - Copies 1 and 2 (Box 28, Folder 1-2)
  - The Body Beautiful, 4.
    - Stage manager's book (Ellis) - Revised October 15, 1957, with holograph note on cover: revision 11-26-57 (Box 28, Folder 3)
  - Ceremonies in Dark Old Men: A Play in Two Acts, 5.
    - Copies 1 and 2 (Box 28, Folder 4-5)
    - Stage manager's book (Box 28, Folder 6)
  - Come Blow Your Horn: A Comedy, 6.
    - Copy 1 (Box 28, Folder 7)
    - Copy 2 (Box 29, Folder 1)
  - Courtin' Time: A Musical Comedy, 7.
    - Version 1 (Box 29, Folder 2)
    - Version 2 with holograph revisions (Box 29, Folder 3)
    - Version 3 with stage manager's book (Box 29, Folder 4)
    - Version 4 (Box 29, Folder 5)
  - Daphne in Cottage D: A Play in Three Acts, 8.
    - Versions 1 and 2 - Order not determined (Box 29, Folder 6-7)
  - Edgar and Alice, 9.
    - Five Star Final - Louis Weitzenkorn as played at the Cort Theatre in New York, January 1931 (Box 29, Folder 8)
  - The Girl in the Freudian Slip, 10.
    - Version 1 (Box 29, Folder 9)
    - Version 2 (Box 30, Folder 1-2)
    - Version 3 - Florida script, March 20, 1967 (Box 30, Folder 3)
    - Version 4 (Box 30, Folder 4-5)
  - Half In Earnest: A Musical Adaptation of the Importance of Being Earnest…, 11.
    - Typescript with holograph and typed revisions and notes (Box 30, Folder 6)
    - I'll Always Remember Miss Whatsername: A Romantic Comedy - Patrick Lawrence (Box 31, Folder 1)
  - Jenny Kissed Me: A Comedy in Three Acts, 12.
    - Stage manager's book (Box 31, Folder 2)
  - The Last Dance (with title: Strange Anniversary), 13.
    - Stage manager's book (Box 31, Folder 3)
    - Line: A Play in Two Acts - Fourth Draft by Israel Horovitz, 1968 (Box 31, Folder 4)
    - The Magistrate - Arthur Wing Pinero (Box 31, Folder 5)
  - Magnolia Alley, 14.
    - Stage manager's book (Ellis) (Box 31, Folder 6)
    - The Marriner Method…A Comedy - Otis Bigelow (Box 31, Folder 7)
    - The Mask - H.M. Harwood? (Box 31, Folder 8)
  - The Mirror Under the Eagle: A Conversation Piece, 15.
    - First draft – Revise to p. 72 (Box 32, Folder 1)
    - Version 2 with sub-title - A play-out, 1958 (Box 32, Folder 2)
  - Mrs. Gibbon's Boys: A Comedy, 16.
    - Typescript with holograph revisions (Box 32, Folder 3)
  - The Name of the Game, 17.
    - Early version as Remember Sweet Alice (Box 32, Folder 4-5)
    - Version 2, November 20, 1965 (Box 32, Folder 6-7)
    - Version 3 as The Name of the Game (Box 32, Folder 8)
    - Version 3 - Copy 2 (Box 33, Folder 1)
    - Version 4, January 1967 (Box 33, Folder 2)
    - Version 5 - Stage manager's script (Box 33, Folder 3)
  - Nothing but the Truth: A Comedy in Three Acts, 18.
    - Samuel French acting edition - Stage manager's copy directed by Ellis at American Church in Paris, April 1938 (Box 33, Folder 4)
  - The Paisley Convertible: A Comedy, 19.
    - Early version - as Early to Bed, 1966 (Box 33, Folder 5-7)
    - As The Paisley Convertible - Copy 1, December 27, 1966 (Box 33, Folder 8)
    - As The Paisley Convertible - Copy 2 (Box 34, Folder 1)
  - A Perfect Frenzy: A Farce Comedy, 20.
    - Stage manager's book for Bucks County 15th Anniversary show (Box 34, Folder 2)
  - The Play's the Thing, 21.
    - Stage manager's book (Box 34, Folder 3)
  - Pueblo: A Play, 22.
    - First draft, April 1, 1970 (Box 34, Folder 4)
  - Remember Sweet Alice, 23.
    - Rollo: A Play in Three Acts - Adapted by Felicity Douglas (Box 34, Folder 5)
  - Sweet Eros and Witness, 24.
    - Final version (Box 34, Folder 6-7)
    - Stage manager's book (Box 34, Folder 8)
  - Twelve Angry Men, 25.
    - Ellis' translation from the French translation for Bucks County - with some stage directions (Box 35, Folder 1-2)
    - French translation: Douze hommes en colere - in L'Avant-scene 184 (Box 35, Folder 3)
  - A Ton of Bricks: A New Comedy, 26.
    - Version 1, September 1961 (Box 35, Folder 4-5)
    - Version 2 - Revision, May 1962 (Box 35, Folder 6)
    - Version 3 - Revision, July 1962 (Box 35, Folder 7)
    - We Call to Mind: A Docudrama - Philip C. Lewis (Box 35, Folder 8)
  - What Did We Do Wrong? A New Comedy, 27.
    - Copies 1 and 2 (Box 35, Folder 9-10)
    - Script changes - Loose pages (Box 35, Folder 11)
    - Which Way the Wind: Docudrama… - Philip C. Lewis, c.1959 (Box 35, Folder 12)
    - A Whiff of Melancholy: A Play in Three Acts - James W. Andres, 1961 (Box 36, Folder 1)
  - Whoever Finds This Bottle, 28.
    - Version C (Box 36, Folder 2)
    - Version 2 (Box 36, Folder 3)
    - Possible final version - Mimeo (Box 36, Folder 4)
  - You Never Know: Musical version of Candlelight, 29.
    - Partial typescript - Samuel French edition of Candlelight included (Box 36, Folder 5)
- Sheet Music, XI.
  Included in this series are scores for The Beauty Part and Half in Earnest. Also includes miscellaneous songs, several from Two's Company, several in more than one version.
  - The Beauty Part - Score (Box 37, Folder 1)
  - The Beauty Part - Bass and Percussion (Box 37, Folder 2)
  - Half in Earnest - Score for Act I (Box 37, Folder 3)
  - Half in Earnest - Score for Act II (Box 37, Folder 4)
  - Half in Earnest - Score for Act III (Box 37, Folder 5)
  - Half in Earnest - Percussion (Box 37, Folder 6)
  - Miscellaneous songs - Titles A-P (Box 37, Folder 7-8)
  - Miscellaneous songs - Titles R-Z (Box 38, Folder 1)
- Scrapbooks, 1954-1956; XII.
  Six scrapbooks cover Michael Ellis' early productions, The Last Dance, The Play's the Thing and Jenny Kissed Me, and the early years at the Bucks County Playhouse, 1954-56. The majority of the scrapbooks contain programs, correspondence, and newspaper clippings. See also additional materials series and oversized material for other scrapbooks.
  - The Last Dance - Chiefly press clippings, 1947-1948 (Box 38, Folder 2)
  - The Play's the Thing - Chiefly press clippings, 1948 (Box 38, Folder 3-4)
  - The Play's the Thing and Jenny Kissed Me, 1948-1949 (Box 39, Folder 1)
  - Bucks County Playhouse, 1954-1956 (Box 39, Folder 2-3)
  - The Beauty Part - Includes clippings and correspondence, 1961-1963 (Box 40, Folder 1-3)
  - Come Blow Your Horn - Includes clippings and correspondence, 1960-1964 (Box 41, Folder 1-2)
  - The Advocate - Chiefly clippings, 1962-1963 (Box 41, Folder 3)
  - Daphne in Cottage D and The Paisley Convertible, 1966-1967 (Box 42, Folder 1)
  - Absence of a Cello - Chiefly clippings and correspondence, 1963-1966 (Box 42, Folder 2)
  - The Girl in the Freudian Slip and What Did We Do Wrong? - Chiefly clippings, 1966-1967 (Box 42, Folder 3)
  - Ceremonies in Dark Old Men, Sweet Eros/Witness, Angela, and Who's Happy Now?, 1968-1969 (Box 43, Folder 1)
- Oversize Miscellany, 1941-1942; XIII.
  The oversize materials in this series are mostly posters, mostly organized by production, A-Z. Also includes a large scrapbook covering Flight to the West (Yardley Theatre, week of Sept. 29, 1941, Michael Ellis' first Equity performance), other early programs, and a significant amount of materials for the production of My Sister Eileen, Eastern Company tour, 1941-42.
  - The Advocate - Mounted Group W newspaper, set designs, and poster at Anta Theater in New York (Box 44, Folder 1)
  - Angela - Poster for the Music Box in New York (Box 44, Folder 2)
  - Ceremonies in Dark Old Men - Two signs (Box 44, Folder 3)
  - Come Blow Your Horn - Posters (Box 44, Folder 4)
  - Courtin' Time - Broadside for Nixon Theatre in Pittsburgh (Box 44, Folder 5)
  - The Girl in the Freudian Slip - Prototype for poster (Box 44, Folder 6)
  - The Play's the Thing - Photograph of Ellis, James Russo, and Faye Emerson also autographed clipping Faye Emerson to "Jimmy" (Box 44, Folder 7)
  - Sweet Eros and The Witness - Poster at Gramercy Arts in New York (Box 44, Folder 8)
  - SUAC (Student Union Academic Commission) presents Mike Ellis - Poster (Box 44, Folder 9)
  - Come Blow Your Horn - Page from Life magazine laminated on wood (Box 44, Folder 10)
  - Scrapbook - Including Flight to the West at the Yardley Theatre and chiefly My Sister Eileen's Eastern Company tour, 1941-1942 (Box 44, Folder 11)
  - Loose photos from scrapbook above (Box 44, Folder 12)
- Addition, 1960-1981; XIV.
  The Kozak Schwart records are the official accounting records for two theatrical limited investment companies formed by Michael Ellis for the production of two plays: Come Blow Your Horn, Broadway, 1961 (Kentwood Company), and Absence of a Cello, Broadway 1963 (Cello Company). The Kentwood Company records date from its formation in 1960 through its dissolution in 1981, but are not complete. The first five years of Cello Company history are also missing; records for 1968-81 are fairly complete. Records for both companies include Statements of Company Condition; correspondence, which contains little of substance; Limited Partnership Agreements; Partners' Share Lists; tax returns; bank statements; and royalty statements. Not all years are represented by the same types of documents within the collection.
  - Kentwood Company, 1960-1981; 1.